Shamsudeen Omotoso

Front-End Developer | Web & Mobile Application Development

. 09032721164

@ shamsudeenomotosho774@gmail.com

Ø linkedin.com/in/shamsudeen-omotoso-927476277
Ø https://portfolio-five-gamma-77.vercel.app/

SUMMARY

I'm a Software Developer | | Front-end with over 1+ years of experience. With a passion for creating interactive, and user-friendly Dynamic web & Mobile Applications. As a Front-End Software Developer, I am devoted to utilizing my acquired programming skills positively impact any organization I am part of. I am a dedicated engineer who gets the job done through a willingness to learn, effective communication, and collaboration.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Alx Academy

= 2022 - 2023 **♀** Online

Worked with a company frontend Developer in creating web applications.

• I attended ALX's 12-month Software Engineering program, specializing in Front-End Development. I collaborated on different projects like Airbnb clone, contributing to the development of dynamic UI interfaces.

Front-End Development Intern

MALhub

苗 2023 👂 Nigeria, Kwara

Worked with a company frontend team in creating new web applications.

- Worked closely with the company's frontend team to conceive and develop cutting-edge web applications, contributing to the enhancement of the overall user experience.
- Collaboratively contributed to the development of an Attendance Management System, which significantly reduced bug fix times by 20%.

Front-End Development Intern

TechnoHacks

= 2023 - 2024 **Q** Onilne

Contributed to the development of proprietary healthcare software solutions.

 I Worked together with industry experts and gain real life practical experience, learning how to manage scalability and Performance Optimization of web Applications .

PROJECTS

Social Media Web Application

 ${\cal O}$ https://project-nextjs-threads.vercel.app/

Developed a comprehensive Threads clone using Next.js 14+, showcasing proficiency in both front-end and back-end technologies.

- Implemented a robust tech stack, incorporating Next.js, MongoDB, Shadcn UI, TailwindCSS, Clerk, and other technologies for optimal performance, security, and scalability.
- Integrated features, including nested deep comments, notifications, realtime search, authentication systems, community creation, member management, and more

STRENGTHS



Analytical and Problem-Solving Skills

Used problem-solving skills to debug and enhance applications, leading to 10% increased user satisfaction at MalHub.



Innovative

Worked closely with cross-functional teams to deliver complex projects on time and within budget.



Teamwork and Collaboration

Successfully adapted to changing project requirements, ensuring seamless integration of new functionalities.

SKILLS

HTML5	CSS3	SASS	/ SCSS	React	
Next JS	JavaScript T		Typescri	pt	
Node JS	Rea	ct Native	Mong	MongoDB	
REST API	Redux Git/GitHub				
TailWind	Material UI		Boots	Bootstrap	
Appwrite CMS GraphQL					
Payload CMS		Firebase	e Netl	ify	
Vercel	ercel Supabase Pr			olving	
Teamwor	k				

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science

Stanford University

苗 2012 - 2014 👂 Stanford, CA

Powered by Shancu

PROJECTS

Event Organizer Web Application

https://price-craft-app-eight.vercel.app/

Developed a comprehensive events management platform using Next.js 14, demonstrating proficiency in full-stack development from concept to execution.

- · Implemented robust Create, Read, Update, and Delete (CRUD) functionalities for events, empowering users with complete control over event management, from creation to modification and deletion.
- Integrated Stripe for seamless and secure payment processing, enabling users to purchase tickets and manage transactions effortlessly.
- Established smart event connections and organized displays, featuring related events on the details page for a structured and user-friendly presentation, elevating engagement and user experience.

Amazon Scrapper Web Application

A https://price-craft-app-eight.vercel.app/

Developed an e-commerce product scraping site using Next.js and Bright Data's webunlocker, empowering users to make informed decisions by receiving notifications on price drops and product availability status.

- · Integrated Nodemailer for automated email notifications, delivering alerts for various scenarios such as back in stock or lowest price. Implemented cron jobs to automate periodic scraping, ensuring real-time and up-to-date data.
- Integrated a user-friendly search bar for efficient input of Amazon product links, enabling seamless scraping and tracking of product details. The site includes a modal for users to opt-in for tracking through email notifications.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in Electrical And **Electronics Engineering**

Kwara State Polytechnic, Ilorin

iii 2022 - Present ♀ Kwara,llorin

Diploma in Software Engineering **ALX Academy**

LANGUAGES

English

Proficient

